#### TONYE DANIEL COLE

Telephone: +447487237437 Email: tjd.cole@gmail.com Portfolio: tjdc94.github.jo/portfolio/

## **PROFILE**

A self-motivated and driven individual with experience in several business environments including Technology, Accounting and Finance, and Private Equity. My background has allowed me to acquire many diverse skills in data mining, data modelling and data analysis. I enjoy working in multi-disciplinary teams to achieve key business objectives and I am a great communicator that can translate complex data and results into reports and summaries that can easily be understood by internal and external stakeholders. I am highly adaptable and have experience working in dynamic teams to time-sensitive deadlines.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python: Pandas & NumPy
- SQL
- R, R Shiny, R Markdown
- HTML5 & CSS3
- Tableau
- SAP & Oracle
- Jira Service Desk
- Microsoft Excel
- Google Analytics
- Amazon Redshift
- Machine Learning Packages: Scikit-learn

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Signal AI, London, United Kingdom Senior Technical Product Analyst

January 2021 - Present

- ⇒ Trained, improved, and deployed AI models to facilitate intelligent decision augmentation for our clients. Trained one AI model-based topic that is now being used by over 50 clients across the globe.
- ⇒ Created a python program that automated a step in the manual source checking process for the support team. This reduced the time spent on this task by 35% and meant the support team had more time to focus on providing customer support to our clients.
- ⇒ Used SQL data processing to extract performance data of the support team and visualised this data using R Markdown in an easy-to-understand format that allowed managers to accurately assess the performance of the team and to set appropriate SLAs. This process led to the average time taken to perform routine tasks reducing by 13%.
- ⇒ Presented my data visualisations in company-wide and cross-functional meetings in a clear and articulate manner. Demonstrating the value that I had brought to the support team & the company
- ⇒ Implemented a process change in Jira Service Desk to reduce the waiting time of our external data labelling providers and help them prioritize tasks in line with our business objectives. This reduced process inefficiency by 5% which equated to 411 hours saved and a saving of over £2,000 per month
- ⇒ Planned and reported on key SLAs and analysed performance metrics within the Product Operations team; delivered these metrics monthly to key stakeholders within the company's leadership team

# Leidenschaft Venture Partners (LV Partners), Lagos, Nigeria Junior Partner

September 2019 – January 2021

- ⇒ Established the company along with 4 experienced Senior Partners in September 2019, the company aims to empower business leaders of the future by providing capital, talent and expertise to help foster transformational growth.
- ⇒ Analysed key metrics & KPIs crucial to the inception and day to day running of the company such as budgets, operating expenses, market research and competitor analyses. This directly led to an investment of \$25,000 in a Data Aggregation platform that has increased its Annual Recurring Revenue to over \$1m per year which represents a growth of over 75% in under 12 months.
- ⇒ Extracted and processed financial data from large databases using SQL and transformed this data into data models using Python. These models were used to drive key data-driven decision-making processes on potential investments.

# Street Capital, Lagos, Nigeria

# Digital Consultant (National Youth Service Corps)

# August 2018 – September 2019

- ⇒ Managed a team of web developers and built websites for clients looking to digitise and optimise their web presence as well as for upcoming industry events.
- ⇒ Carried out a design audit for a top Nigerian bank to optimise their web & IOS applications and improve customer engagement. This audit discovered that the bank's app had a retention rate of 78% thus I suggested a redesign of the app's UI/UX to improve the usability and accessibility of the product. This resulted in an increased retention rate of 84% and increased engagement on the Bank's mobile banking platform.
- ⇒ Created a data visualisation tool using Tableau to aid in election data collection and canvassing for the national elections in Nigeria. The software allowed complex census data such as population demographics, occupation and previous voting

patterns to be mined and visualised on a web app. The insights resulted in more efficient resource allocation allowing the client to use their budget more effectively and reduce the expected cost of campaigning by approximately \mathbb{\text{4}}600 million (£1.2 million).

## PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC), London, UK

#### September 2016 - March 2018

#### IT Risk Assurance Associate

- ⇒ Analysed and cross-referenced client's financial data to ensure that internal controls were in place to mitigate key business risks for companies across industries such as Life Sciences, Telecoms and Logistics. For example, during an engagement with a leading Life Science Company in the UK; my work to optimise the client's internal control frameworks reduced their cost associated with logistics by 7%.
- ⇒ Reviewed client annual financial reports to provide assurance that these reports met PCAOB auditing standards.
- ⇒ Prepared and reviewed proposal documentation used by senior management to bid for new multi-million-pound client engagements.
- ⇒ Held an editorial position at the Africa Business Group and was responsible for sending out monthly publications across the firm's wide global network. Showcasing my strong written communication skills.
- ⇒ Utilised SAP & Oracle implementations for clients in healthcare, telecoms and FMCG as well as SQL & R for data-driven decision-making processes. In conjunction with SQL, I used Tableau to visualise the data for client presentations, for Senior Partners and Directors. I routinely used R to create supervised machine learning models based on multiple linear regression and support vector regression.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# **Behavioural Health Institute (BHI)**

May 2019 -August 2020

#### **Board Member & Founder**

- ⇒ Founded the Behavioural Health Institute in May 2019 to provide mental health support for sufferers across Nigeria.
- ⇒ Hold a seat on the organisation's board of trustees along with top physicians, mental health professionals and government officials
- ⇒ Led high-level discussions with the board of trustees and an external strategic consultant to define the organisation's short-term goals, long-term goals, organisational structure and revenue model.
- ⇒ Organised an event during Mental Health Awareness Week in 2019 where we welcomed over 500 guests to a day of seminars from mental health professionals on subjects ranging from post-natal depression to the mental effect of domestic abuse.

# **United Nations Volunteers**

**January 2017 – June 2017** 

Volunteer

⇒ Volunteered online for the United Nation to support the creation and design of a website as well as to create working papers and presentations for a refugee outreach programme in Cameroon.

Lani Foundation June 2013 – July 2013

Volunteer

- ⇒ Researched and analysed data trends on orphans and resource distribution in Nigerian orphanages.
- ⇒ Synthesised a detailed report and visual presentation to senior management which led to a round of visits to 5 local orphanages to re-distribute food, school supplies and medicine.

# **EDUCATION**

## Cass Business School, London, UK: MSc Supply Chain Management

1st Class (Distinction)

2015 - 2016

Key modules: Supply Chain Management & Finance, Managing Operations, Business Sustainability, Quantitative Methods for Business, Supply Chain Forecasting & Decision Analysis

#### Cass Business School, London, UK: Summer School

2015 - 2015

Module: Introduction to Quantitative Methods: 81%

# University of Sheffield, UK: BSc Biochemistry & Microbiology

2.1 (Honours)

2012 - 2015

Project: Computational bioinformatics project using the python programming language

Constructed programs to analyse and extract data of interest from a dataset; wrote a 12,000-word report on data processing results *Dissertation:* 6,000-word literary review investigating the potential uses of halophilic enzymes as biocatalysts

## Repton School, Derbyshire, UK: A-Levels

2007 - 2012

Biology A, Chemistry A, History A

Headmaster's Achievement Prize awarded for outstanding academic excellence

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

Languages: Native English speaker, conversational French speaker

**Sports:** Member of a 5 aside football team and a boxing club

Clubs and Societies: Member of the Cass Toastmasters Society have received the Most Improved Speaker Award

Music: Achieved the ABRSM percussion Grade 5 qualification